Beirut, Lebanon

🛘 (+961) 71-778924 | 🗷 wissam.antoun@gmail.com | 🤻 wissamantoun.github.io | 🗖 wissamantoun | 🎓 Wissam Antoun

Summary.

Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning Engineer specialised in state-of-the-art Natural Language Processing techniques. Within 1 year, I had developed my knowledge of NLP and published one the most famous and powerful AI models for Arabic text representation. I also ranked in top places in almost all AI competitions that i participated in. In addition, I have 2 years of experience in teaching as a Graduate Teaching Assistant at the Eng. faculty at AUB and through online sessions. I'm self-motivated, self-taught and a performer when working on tight deadlines. I'm also a tech geek who loves computer hardware and technology, and enjoys DIY projects and gaming.

Work Experience

Zaka Online

Al Instructor May. 2020

• Gave a 4-part online workshop series titled A Comprehensive NLP series that was focused on delivering the major NLP concepts through handson coding examples along with the NLP fundamentals theory. Concepts ranged from Bag-of-Words, Word Embeddings, Advanced Deeplearning Models for text, and transformer-based architectures

Stars of Science Doha, Qatar

Feb. 2020 - Apr. 2020 MACHINE LEARNING EXPERT

· Provided Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence solutions as part of the support team that helps each contestant throughout their Stars of Science journey

Reviewer

REVIEWER FOR THE FOLLOWING JOURNALS:

2020

- Expert Systems with Applications www.journals.elsevier.com/expert-systems-with-applications
- Journal of King Saud University Computer and Information Sciences

www.journals.elsevier.com/journal-of-king-saud-university-computer-and-information-sciences

MIND Lab (Prof. Hazem Hajj) - American University of Beirut

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Sep. 2018 - Current

- My research focuses on state-of-the-art NLP technologies for natural language understanding, generation, and social chatbots.
- · Worked on pre-training various Arabic language models that ranges from RNN-based to the Transformer-based models, using Cloud TPU and GPU instances.

ECE Dept. - American University of Beirut

Beirut, Lebanon

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- EECE 435L: Software Tools Lab, Co-Instructor (3 semesters). Delivered a range of teaching and assessment activities including tutorials directed towards the delivery of modern Software Tools at the undergraduate level. Prepared lab tutorials, graded assignments and provided support for the student projects.
- EECE 696: Applied Parallel Programming, Lab instructor (1 semester). Delivered hands-on experience to graduate students on parallel programming and GPU computing using the CUDA C/C++ framework on local computers and on AWS. Provided office hours, assignment grading and support for course project.
- EECE 330: Data Structures and Algorithms, Lab instructor (1 semester). Delivered hands-on experience on fundamental algorithms and data structures used in software applications at the undergraduate level using C++. Provided weekly assessments, feedback, and support.
- Introduced a plagiarism detection tool for computer code to the Electrical Engineering Department.

Huawei Technologies (Lebanon) S.A.R.L.

Beirut, Lebanon

INTERN

June 2016 - Aug. 2016

· Learned about various LTE principles, base station hardware, and Microwave transmissions systems.

Publications

AraBERT: Transformer-based Model for Arabic Language Understanding

Antoun, Wissam, Fady Baly, and Hazem Hajj

Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Open-Source Arabic Corpora and Processing Tools at LREC 2020, 2020, Marseille, France

Multi-Task Learning using AraBert for Offensive Language Detection

Djandji, Marc, Fady Baly, Wissam Antoun, and Hazem Hajj

Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Open-Source Arabic Corpora and Processing Tools at LREC 2020, 2020, Marseille, France

State of the Art Models for Fake News Detection Tasks

Antoun, Wissam, Fady Baly, Rim Achour, Amir Hussein, and Hazem Hajj

2020 IEEE International Conference on Informatics, IoT, and Enabling Technologies (ICIoT) (ICIoT'2020), 2020, Doha, Qatar

hULMonA: The Universal Language Model in Arabic

ElJundi, Obeida, Wissam Antoun, Nour El Droubi, Hazem Hajj, Wassim El-Hajj, and Khaled Shaban

Proceedings of the Fourth Arabic Natural Language Processing Workshop at ACL, 2019, Florence, Italy

NOVEMBER 17, 2020 WISSAM ANTOUN · RÉSUMÉ A Comprehensive Approach for A Smart Medication Dispenser Kassem, Abdallah, **Wissam Antoun**, Mustapha Hamad, and Chady El-Moucary

International Journal of Computing and Digital Systems 8.02 (2019) PP. 131-141. UNIVERSITY OF BAHRAIN, 2019

Smart Medicine Dispenser (SMD)

Antoun, Wissam, Ali Abdo, Suleiman Al-Yaman, Abdallah Kassem, Mustapha Hamad, and Chady El-Moucary 2018 IEEE 4th Middle East Conference on Biomedical Engineering (MECBME), 2018

Real-Time Fire Detection Using CUDA

Antoun, Wissam and Manal Jalloul

ISC High Performance, Poster Presentation, 2019, Frankfurt, Germany

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

Second Place, OSACT4-Shared task on Offensive Language Detection
 Best Domain Detection system, Qatar International Fake News Detection and Annotation Contest

Doha, Qatar

DOMESTIC

Second Place, Mindsets-OLX Datathon, Best car price prediction score. (www.kaggle.com/c/mindsets)
 First place, Big Data, AI, and Media Hackathon Powered by Touch and Anghami

AUB, Lebanon
AUB, Lebanon

Presentations

High Performance Computing for Lebanon (HPC4L) Brown Bag

Beirut, Lebanon

PRESENTER FOR CURRENT AND FUTURE/POTENTIAL USE CASES FOR HPC4L

Feb. 2020

May. 2020

- Introduced the use case of HPC for pretraining transformer-based model for Arabic language Understanding
- Explained parallelization and scaling techniques for transformer models

PyData Khobar meetup Online

PRESENTER FOR ARABERT: PRETRAINING, USE CASES AND FUTURE IMPROVEMENTS

· Introduced the AraBERT model for the Arab community and explained the pretraining and fine-tuning procedure

Education

Masters Of Engineering In Electrical And Computer Engineering

Beirut, Lebanon Feb. 2018 - Current

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF BEIRUT

• Major Area: Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning systems

CCNA Routing And Switching: Introduction To Networks

- Minro Area: Software, Networking and Security
- Awarded Graduate Fellowship with full tuition coverage

Bachelor Of Engineering In Computer And Communication Engineering

Zouk Mosbeh, Lebanon

NOTRE DAME UNIVERSITY - LOUAIZE

Fall. 2014 - Summer 2017

• GPA: 3.58 Dean's List for 6 semesters

Zouk Mosbeh, Lebanon

CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY- NOTRE DAME UNIVERSITY

Sep 2016 - Jan 2017

Skills

 Python
 TensorFlow
 PyTorch
 Keras
 Bash
 Git
 CUDA
 Parallel Programming
 C++
 C#
 Matlab
 Java
 SQL
 LaTex

 VSCode

November 17, 2020 Wissam Antoun · Résumé 2